Jason Hutchens

Contact 16B Brian Avenue

Mount Pleasant, W.A. AUSTRALIA 6153 +61~4~3323~1010 JasonHutchens@gmail.com https://www.kranzky.com

Profile

Skilled programmer and leader with over two decades of industry experience across a variety of technologies and industries seeking to work remotely from Perth, Australia on challenging and fun projects where I can make a measurable improvement to product quality.

SKILLS

Ruby, Vue, Flutter, Rust, Python, C, SQL, JavaScript, spelunking legacy code.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (IT), University of Western Australia 1991-1994

PhD Research (incomplete), University of Western Australia 1995-1999

EXPERIENCE

Lead Engineer/CTO, Robots+Rockets/GroupFire LLC March 2015—March 2020

- Managed a fully remote team of up to a dozen developers, designers and QA.
- Wrote a data analytics and reporting engine, with a realtime user engagement front-end.
- Implemented dynamic code push updates for mobile apps to facilitate quick rollout of changes.
- Added realtime messaging, video processing and social media monitoring to our product.
- Developed a dynamic heatmap of user locations to enable geospatial search by administrators.

Head of Development/Head of R&D, Agworld Pty. Ltd. July 2011—March 2015

- Implemented a dependency-driven event queue to recalculate expensive derived data.
- Developed a unit conversion extension to ActiveRecord, with a clear separation of concerns.
- Designed and implemented a stand-alone sync server for iPad data to replace RhoSync.
- Wrote technical project documentation that led to us winning a cash-cow project.
- Took over a reporting project and worked with the team to refactor it under intense pressure.

Senior Geophysical Software Engineer, DownUnder GeoSolutions January 2011—June 2011

- Worked on well bore visualisation, correlation and mistie correction.
- Fixed numerous minor issues in the codebase that were the root cause of many bugs.

Consultant, Titan Interactive February 2010—June 2010

- Improved throughput from three to twelve websites launched per week.
- Specified and designed an email campaign manager and oversaw its development.

Project Manager, Living Years March 2009—May 2010

- Specified requirements, identified risks, and hired a development team.
- Launched the project within six months to successfully hit an immovable deadline.

Lead Programmer, Interzone Games February 2007—February 2009

- Led a team of 13 very good programmers and spent half my time writing code.
- Worked with other teams to ensure features were feasible and accurately estimated.
- Designed and implemented the physics engine with both client and server components.

AI Team Lead, Team Bondi October 2004—February 2007

- Designed AI technology and implemented the bulk of the design in C++.
- Interviewed, hired, mentored and supervised a team of six developers.
- Wrote tools to allow game designers to enter and maintain data relevant to the game.

Programmer, Nautronix January 2003—October 2004

- Wrote a tool to process large volumes of multi-channel audio data.
- Implemented a complete system to manage submarine testing and oversaw its installation.

Chief Scientist, Artificial Intelligence July 2000—September 2001

- Performed research and implemented the resulting algorithms in C++.
- Worked to establish an online laboratory for public experiments.
- Devised and announced the "Learning Machine Challenge" at the AAAI conference.

Programmer, Lionhead Studios December 1999—June 2000

- Wrote a bytecode compiler for a scripting language of my design.
- Implemented a VM with support for multiple virtual threads and multitasking.
- Set up a mock game API to allow scripts to be compiled and tested outside of the game.

Founding Director, Amristar September 1999—January 2003

- Worked for a local real estate company to develop an interactive mapping technology in Java.
- Designed and built a centralised workflow operations system for a chain of mechanics.

Research Assistant, CSIRO January 1990—December 1990

- Wrote programs in QuickBasic and ported legacy Fortran code.
- Used CAD software to prepare 3D schematics for publication.

Please see my LinkedIn profile for testimonials from former colleagues.

- Jonty Barnes (Lionhead), Head of Production, Bungie (jontyb@microsoft.com).
- Ben Board (Team Bondi), Developer Manager, Microsoft (ben_board@yahoo.com).
- Yaki Dunietz, President, Artificial Intelligence (yaki@a-i.com).
- Dr. Michael Alder (PhD Supervisor), UWA (mike@maths.uwa.edu.au).

References